DANIEL OTIENO OKWACH

Address: Kongowea, Mombasa, Kenya.

Phone number: (+254) 720057533 / 773991561.

Email: danielotieno.ke@gmail.com.

Career Objective

To use my qualifications and experience to support the enterprise realize it is objectives as well as gain important practical experience, skills and knowledge as I work towards realizing my potential and enhance my career development.

Education

2013-2017: Technical University of Mombasa

Award - Degree (Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and Computer Science).

2013-2013: Sponsor an African Scholar (SAAS)

Award – Certificate in computer operations (4 months course)

2009-2012: Mariakani Secondary School

Award – Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (K.C.S.E)

Profile

An energetic, creative and imaginative young Software Developer who is able and dedicated to work alongside other talented IT professionals in creating websites to the very highest standards. I have specialized in both Front-end and Backend Development, experienced with all stages of the development cycle for a dynamic project, well-versed in numerous programming languages including Ruby, Python and JavaScript. I also have interest in Data Analysis using Python and SPSS. I am open to considering a challenging role with an ambitious company with whom I can commit to and progress within.

Achievements and Leadership Positions

- **2017-present:** Organizer of Nairuby Mombasa (Rubyists user group in Mombasa).
- **2016:** Won award for the best personality student of the year.
- 2015 2017: Elected Class Representative (Technical University of Mombasa).
- **2014:** Elected Vice Chairperson (SAAS Youth Group).
- **2011:** Won award for the best personality student of the year.
- 2009 2012: Elected Deputy Class president (Mariakani Sec School).

Professional Experience

Andela Learning Community

2019 - Present

Learning Facilitator Ambassador (Volunteering)

Key activities and responsibilities:

- Organize and facilitate ALC meetups.
- Make sure more than 50% learner completion of 100% of course contents and projects.
- Make sure more than 75% learner completion of 50-75% of course contents and projects.
- Run 2 meetups between January and February 2019.
- Mentor learners on their online engagement platforms.

Freelance 2017 - Present

Key activities and responsibilities:

- Writing cross-browser compliant XHTML, HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.
- Develop project concept and maintain optimal workflow.
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks.
- Collaborate with designers to create a clean interfaces.
- Collaborate with other developers through web-based hosting service for version control using git.
- Providing technical support to the end user.

Sponsor an African Scholar

2016 - 2017

IT Administrator

Key activities and responsibilities:

- Maintaining the organization IT network.
- Collecting IT usage statistics.
- Installation of software's.
- Making recommendations for improving the organization website.
- Assisting co-workers with everyday IT needs.

SwahiliBox April 2015- Aug 2015

Web Developer Intern

Worked as part of a multi-disciplinary team, carrying out ad-hoc tasks as requested by the IT Manager. Had a specific brief to ensure the websites build for customer's precisely matched their requirements.

Key activities and responsibilities:

Performed maintenance and updates to existing client Web sites.

- Participated in brainstorming sessions to come up with ideas.
- Documented software and technical specifications.
- Addressed cross-browser compatibility issues.
- Integrated websites with social media platforms.
- Helped end users to solve operating problems.
- Worked on multiple projects simultaneously to a high standard.
- Developing and maintaining the front-end functionality of websites.
- Devising SEO strategies based on specific keywords.
- Participating in discussions with clients to clarify what they want.

Omollo Onyango Advocates & Company

Aug 2014 – Feb 2015

Office Junior

Key activities and responsibilities:

- Arranging files in the office.
- Helped in troubleshooting office computers.
- Preparing affidavits.
- Configuring office Wi-Fi.
- Storing files in the system.

Key Competencies and Skills

Web Development

- Knowledge of RUBY, PYTHON, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Strategically thinking through all parts of the design process.
- Integrating new technologies into existing web properties.
- Writing up technical manuals and user instructions.
- Experience of Object-Oriented Programming and Continuous Integration.

Professional

- Able to organize own workload effectively and prioritize tasks.
- High level of proficiency in Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook).
- Can manage multiple projects in a fast-paced, deadline-driven environment.
- Adaptable and able to quickly pick up new techniques.
- Understanding of W3C standards, web accessibility & best practice.

Personal

- Passionate about doing a good job.
- First-rate interpersonal and communication skills, able to easily interact with fellow developers and customers alike.
- Comfortable with being the 'go to' person in a company.
- Always positive, regardless of the challenge ahead.
- Willingness to work with emerging alternative technologies.
- An excellent ability to work both as a team player and as an effective leader.

Interest/Activities

Personal interests are traveling and exploring, photographing, swimming, playing games such as Soccer and touch rugby.

Referees

Dr. Aggrey Adem

Director of TUM Enterprise Technical University of Mombasa

Mobile: +254 721261415

Email: aggreyadem@gmail.com

Mr. Aly Salim Uweso

Deputy Executive Director SwahiliBox Enterprise (M-Power)

Mobile: +254 711763249

Email: alysalim1981@gmail.com

Ms. Maria Nekesa

Chief Administrative Officer SPONSOR AN AFRICAN SCHOLAR

Mobile: +254 724348945 Email: maria@saas.ie